In that very first step, we are going to first construct a middleware, okay.
Okay, so what we can do actually is, we can go to this back and folder and we can create
with, like we can create this one middleware and folder, so it is going to connect the
front end and the back end.
Like for that basic purpose we used middleware, but in this case we are going to just use
this auth middleware.js, we are going to make this auth middleware.js file, okay.
So now, inside of this, what we can actually do is import JWT, okay.
So import JWT from JSON, web token and do one thing, import user from dot.slasmodel/user model.js
and export cons, we are going to make a one function, which is called as check auth, okay.
So check auth and same, we are going to assign this as a sync a request and the response and
then the next one, this is actually wrong, so response and next, okay.
So now, again the same concept which we will be using, like try and cache blocks or try
and cache, here it would be error, okay. So we are going to verify that about the user,
okay. So which user is present. So first we are going to make this middleware, I am going
to explain UI, we are making this middleware, so bear with me. So equal to request dot cookie,
so we are going to get the value of the JWT from the cookies and after this, we are just
going to check if there is no token, okay. So there is no token or the token doesn't exist.
In that case, we are going to just return the RES. status of 400.json token is invalid,
okay. So the token is invalid and now after this, okay, this type of I guess, so after
this since token is required, we are going to implement another conditions like we are going
to just use this decode, okay. So const decode equal to JWT dot verify, verify, we are going
to verify whether the token exists or not and after that if this token exists, we are going
to verify the token, we are the secret key that we have already made, so process dot nv dot c correct
key, okay. Secret key. So after this, if this decoded value doesn't exist, we are going
to check here also like whether this decoded value doesn't exist. In that case, we are going
to return the status, so return the status as 401 dot JSON and message unauthorized invalid
token, invalid token. So basically why we are making this is, we have to verify the token
like whether it is coming from an existing user or not, okay. If this is not a valid token,
then we cannot change our profile, right. So that's why, like we cannot make a change in our
profile, if it's not a authorized user. That's why we are making this a auth middleware,
okay. So here const await user dot find by ID, so find by ID and so we are going to use
that decoded value, so decoded value user dot ID and we are going to select the field
of password. So dot select and then password and after this, again, we are going to check
whether if this user is existing or not. So if this user doesn't exist, like we have already
done in the previous video. So res dot status, sorry, as dot status, 404 dot JSON and we are going
to just pass that that user is not found. So message user not found, okay. So now we are going
to again get that user from the user and we are going to implement this next, okay. So next
function. So it's automatically going to pass to the next function. So that is why it is used.
So export const check out. So we are going to take the token from the JWT, we are going
to verify the token with that if this token exists or not, if this token doesn't exist,
then we are going to pass this status as res dot status 400 dot JSON, that token is invalid,
okay. Otherwise, if the token exists, then we are going to take that token inside of our
decoded value and we are going to check whether this decoded value exists or not.
If this doesn't exist, then again, we are going to pass the message as unauthorized invalid
token. So this is not coming from a verified user. Then after that, if the user exists
in this case, so we are going to store the value of the user by decoded user ID.
So decode dot user ID and we are going to select the field as password. And if that particular
user is not found, again, we are going to add check here. Then in that case also, we are
going to say that user is not found. Otherwise, we are going to take the user's value
from the request, so request dot user equal to user and the next function is going to
call the next function in the middleware. So again, in this one, what we are going to do
like in the cache block also, simply we are going to pass the error, whatever it comes
to console dot LOG that some kind of error is coming. So error in checkout middleware.
So to have the authenticity of a particular user, whether it exists or not or whether this
is a verified user or not, it is coming, the message is coming from the verified user.
We are using this or the middleware dot here, okay.